<!--
	## Section 0: Main
    Introduction: @string/introduction
	
	### Section 0: Main
	- Introduction: @string/introduction
	- References and Credit: @string/references

	### Section 1: Avoiding Harm
	- Active Shooters: @string/active
	- Disease and Infection: @string/disease
	- Escaping a Multistory: @string/escaping
	- Explosive Devices: @string/explosive
	- Medical Treatment: @string/medical
	- Minimizing Injury: @string/minimizing
	- NBC Attacks: @string/nbc1
	- NBC Decontamination: @string/nbc2
	- Violent Riot: @string/violent
	- Transportation Troubles: @string/transportation

	### Section 2: Clandestine Activities
	- Avoiding Detection: @string/avoiding
	- Barricading Techniques: @string/barricading
	- Circumvent Security: @string/circumvent

	### Section 3: Fighting Back
	- Basic Combatives: @string/basic
	- Disarming Opponents: @string/disarming
	- Firefighting: @string/firefighting
	- Improvised Weapons: @string/improvised
	- Restraining Devices: @string/restraining

	### Section 4: Getting Help
	- Codes: @string/codes
	- Signals: @string/signals
	- Telecommunications: @string/telecommunications
-->

<resources>
	
	<!-- These are Menu Titles -->
	<string name="app_name">RHF Manual</string>
	
	<string name="category0">Main</string>
    <string name="introduction">Introduction</string>
	<string name="references">References and Credits</string>
	
	<string name="category1">Avoiding Harm</string>
	<string name="active">Active Shooter</string>
    <string name="disease">Disease and Infection</string>
	<string name="escaping">Escaping a Multistory</string>
	<string name="explosive">Explosive Devices</string>
    <string name="medical">Medical Treatment</string>
	<string name="minimizing">Minimizing Injury</string>
    <string name="nbc1">NBC Attacks</string>
	<string name="nbc2">NBC Decontamination</string>
    <string name="transportation">Transportation Troubles</string>
	<string name="violent">Violent Rioting</string>
	
	<string name="category2">Clandestine Activities</string>
    <string name="avoiding">Avoiding Detection</string>
    <string name="barricading">Barricading Technique</string>
    <string name="circumvent">Circumvent Security</string>
	
	<string name="category3">Fighting Back</string>
    <string name="basic">Basic Combatives</string>
    <string name="disarming">Disarming Opponents</string>
    <string name="firefighting">Firefighting</string>
    <string name="improvised">Improvised Weapons</string>
    <string name="restraining">Restraining Devices</string>
	
	<string name="category4">Getting Help</string>
    <string name="codes">Codes</string>
    <string name="signals">Signals</string>
    <string name="telecommunications">Telecommunications</string>
	
    <!-- These are actual Menu Text -->
    
    <string name="referencesText">
		Text CONTENT referencesText
    </string>
    
    <string name="activeText">
		Text CONTENT activeText
    </string>
    
    <string name="diseaseText">
		Text CONTENT diseaseText
    </string>
    
    <string name="escapingText">
		Text CONTENT escapingText
    </string>
    
    <string name="explosiveText">
		Text CONTENT explosiveText
    </string> 
    
    <string name="medicalText">
		Text CONTENT medicalText
    </string>
    
    <string name="minimizingText">
		Text CONTENT minimizingText
    </string>
    
    <string name="nbc1Text">
		Text CONTENT nbc1Text
    </string>
    
    <string name="nbc2Text">
		Text CONTENT nbc2Text
    </string>
    
    <string name="transportationText">
		Text CONTENT transportationText
    </string>
    
    <string name="violentText">
		Text CONTENT violentText
    </string>
    
    <string name="avoidingText">
		Text CONTENT avoidingText
    </string>
    
    <string name="barricadingText">
		Text CONTENT barricadingText
    </string>
    
    <string name="circumventText">
		Text CONTENT circumventText
    </string>
    
    <string name="basicText">
		Text CONTENT basicText
    </string>
    
    <string name="disarmingText">
		Text CONTENT disarmingText
    </string>
    
    <string name="improvisedText">
		Text CONTENT improvisedText
    </string>
    
    <string name="restrainingText">
		Text CONTENT restrainingText
    </string> 
    
    <string name="codesText">
		Text CONTENT codesText
    </string>
    
    <string name="signalsText">
		Text CONTENT signalsText
    </string>
    
    <string name="telecommunicationsText">
		Text CONTENT telecommunicationsText
    </string>

	<string name="introductionText">
        <b>If you are in an emergency situation at this moment, ignore this page and tap the top left-hand icon to bring up the menu so you can get to the information you need.</b>\n\n
        This mobile app contains information which can help guide you through emergency situations. While most, if not all, of the information contained will never be useful to you, the information is still fun to read about and can help you if you do manage to get yourself into an emergency situation.\n\n
        The most important parts of the app are in <b>bold</b>, so if you don\'t have time to read through everything, you\'ll know what\'s the important stuff. Also make sure to take a look at the pictures, as they may help more than words.\n\n
        This app references the following:\n
        - FM 3-3: Chemical and Biological Contamination Avoidance\n
        - FM 3-3.1: Nuclear Contamination Avoidance\n
        - FM 3-5: NBC Decontamination\n
        - FM 4-25.11: First Aid\n
        - FM 12-80: Kill, or Get Killed\n
        - FM 21-10: Field Hygiene and Sanitation\n
        - FM 21-60: Visual Signals\n
        - FM 21-150: Combatives\n
        - FM 55-501: Marine Crewman\'s Handbook\n
        - Other texts\n\n
        Hopefully you\'ll never encounter any of the situations this app deals with, but if you do, don\'t worry, you\'ve increased your survival chance by a statistically insignificant amount! :D\n\n
        Seriously though, if you actually need this app, then I really wish you the best of luck. Happy surviving!\n\n
        This app was created for the Congressional App Challenge.
    </string>
	<string name="firefightingText">
		<b>The fire classes are based on the United States fire classification system.</b>\n
		<b>The fire classes are based on the United States fire classification system.</b>\n\n
		<b>FIRE CLASSIFICATION</b>\n
      There are six classes of fires:\n
		<b>Class A</b>: Fire consists of <b>ordinary combustibles such as wood, paper, and fabric</b>. This is usually the most common and easiest fire to put out.\n
		<b>Class B</b>: Fire consists of <b>flammable or combustible liquid or gas</b>. Never use water on these, as water may spread the fire and worsen the situation.\n
		<b>Class C</b>: Fire consists of <b>potentially energized electrical equipment</b>. Never use water or foam on these, as electricity may travel through the conductive agent into your body, risking injury or death. In Europe, this is no longer recognized as a class as electricity is not the source of the fire. If the electrical current is disabled, then the fire may be fought without risking accidental electrocution.\n
		<b>Class D</b>: Fire consists of <b>combustible metals, especially alkali metals</b>. Different metals have different methods of control; while water may work on one metal, it may cause further chemical reactions for other metals.\n
		<b>Class K</b>: Fire consists of <b>unsaturated cooking oils</b>. This is actually a subcategory of Class B fires, and can be treated as such. The central difference is that water mist (but not a solid stream of water) can be used to extinguish the fire.\n\n
		<b>FIRE SUPPRESSION EQUIPMENT</b>\n
		Fire requires four things to operate effectively: Oxygen, Fuel, Heat, and a Sustainable Chain Reaction to keep the fire burning. There are usually six types of fire extinguisher equipment at hand:\n
		- Water Extinguishers: One of the classic and cost-effective ways to fight fires, they spray water to decrease Heat and soak into the material, if applicable. <b>They have a red label, and should be used to fight Class A fires, but NOT Class B. Class C, or Class K fires</b>.\n
		- Foam Extinguishers: They extinguish by eliminating the Oxygen element. <b>They have a cream label, and should be used to fight Class A and Class B fires, but never Class C fires</b>.\n
      	- Carbon Dioxide Extinguishers: They extinguish fires by eliminating the Oxygen and Heat elements of a fire. <b>They have a black label, and should be used to fight Class B or Class C fires.</b>
      	- Dry Chemical Extinguishers: They extinguish fires by eliminating the Sustainable Chain Reaction element of a fire. <b>They have a blue label, and should be used for Class B and Class C fires. However, some (particularly the multipurpose extinguishers that you commonly see) may also be suitable for Class A fires, but make sure that the fire gets fully extinguished.</b>\n
      	- Wet Chemical Extinguishers: They extinguish fires by eliminating the Heat and Sustainable Chain Reaction elements of a fire. <b>They have a yellow label, and while they are primarily designed to extinguish Class K fires, they can also be used to extinguish Class A and Class B fires.</b>\n
		- Dry Powder Extinguishers: They extinguish fires by eliminating the Heat or Oxygen element. <b>They have a blue label, and are intended for Class D fires only.</b>
      	- Fire Blanket: They extinguish fires eliminating the Oxygen element. <b>They are primarily designed to extinguish Class K fires, but can also be used to extinguish a person who is on fire.</b>\n\n
		<b>USING AN EXTINGUISHER</b>
		<b>Only fight a fire if the fire is very small and you know how to do it safely.</b> If you are going to use an extinguisher, makes sure you have an escape route behind you as you fight the flames.\n
		First, using the proper extinguisher and starting from a safe distance away, put a hand on the neck of the extinguisher for stability. Then, <b>rip off the pin</b> to remove both the pin and the cable tie-looking tamper seal.\n
		Then, <b>aim the hose of the extinguisher towards the base of the flames</b>. The flames themselves aren\'t solid, and if you aim at the flames themselves, the extinguishing agent will go right through the fire.\n
		Once you\'re ready, <b>squeeze the top handle/lever</b>, which releases the extinguishing agent from the fire extinguisher.\n
		Finally, while slowly moving forward, <b>sweep the nozzle from side to side until the fire is gone. Make sure to watch out for any reignitions when you\'re done.</b> You should have 30 to 60 seconds of water or 10 to 25 seconds of dry chemical.\n
    </string>
	

</resources>