<resources>
<string name="violentText">
"<b><big>INTRODUCTION</big></b>
    A riot is a form of civil disorder characterized by a group lashing out in a violent public disturbance. Riots will likely include theft, vandalism, and destruction of both public and private property. 
 <b><big>ESCAPING A RIOT</big></b>
    If you are on foot, move with the crowd while getting closer to the edge of the riot. Do not try to resist the movement or you may fall and be trampled. Avoid intervening with the destruction of property and the injury of people. Try to get to the nearest building, but avoid prime looting targets such as stores, restaurants, religious institutions, or government buildings; even if looters don't end up looting such buildings, you may be viewed as a potential looter by riot police.
    If you are in a vehicle, you will likely be targeted by rioters. Avoid slowing down, and maintain a constant speed. Never accelerate directly into a crowd. Never risk committing vehicular homicide.
 <b><big>RIOT CONTROL WEAPONS</big></b>
    These are the most common riot control weapons to be aware of:
    - Club: Made of either wood, rubber, plastic, or metal, clubs (the most iconic being the baton) are intended as a non-lethal compliance tool. Avoid getting hit in the head and neck, as they may cause concussions, skull/spinal fractures, or death,
    - Bean Bag Round: Fired from modified shotguns, a bean bag round contains lead pellets, all of which are expelled in a wide spray. Avoid getting hit in the head, neck, and chest due to the possibility of bone fracture.
    - Riot Shield: A component in virtually all riot police units, riot shields are intended to both protect the user from melee attacks and thrown projectiles and to push back rioters. Riot shields are usually transparent, and most rarely offer complete ballistic protection. If armed opposition is expected, then ballistic shields (which are usually not transparent) will be used. Avoid pushing back against these sheilds, as you may fall and be trampled.
    - Rubber Bullets: Unlike their metal counterparts, rubber bullets are intended to cause pain and only minor injury. Avoid getting hit in the head, neck, and back. Make sure to seek medical attention if you have been shot to ensure that no internal bleeding has occured.
    - Tear Gas: Tear gas affects breathing, and causes skin and eye irritation. They are fired as canisters into the rioting crowd. If you become affected by tear gas, get out of the area of the canister. Although your eye vision may become blurry, do not blindly run around as you risk running into traffic. Flush the irritated areas with clearn water and take a cold/lukewarm shower (hot water opens the pores and allows gas particles into your body) to flush away the chemical.
    - Water Cannon: These fire a strong jet of water and are intended to knock over rioters. Stay low to avoid getting easily hit by the jet, and do not slip on the water. If you are knocked over/slip, crawl to safety.
"
</string>
</resources>