<resources>
<string name="restrainingText">
"   <b><big>INTRODUCTION</big></b>
    To stay safe while being kidnapped/held hostage, it's advised that you cooperate with your captors and avoid confrontation. Nevertheless, if you see an opportunity to make an escape, freeing yourself from your restraints will be your first task.

    <b><big>CABLE TIES</big></b>
    A common method of illegal restraint is the use of cable ties (also called zip ties). There are several way to escape cable ties:

    Prior to being tied, make fists and put them next to each other. They will have created enough slack in the cable tie such that it is possible to escape by rotating your fists and pulling your hands out.

    If you have bobby pins or other thin pieces of metal, you can wedge them in between the ratchet and the interlocking teeth. You can then pull out the tape without the tape getting caught in the teeth.

    Because cable ties are made of plastic, you can wear them down by sawing them against a rough surface.

    Finally, as a method of last resort, you can try to break apart the cable tie. This is a method of last resort as the cable tie must be fully tightened around your wrists. Once you do so, raise your hands and bring them down to your stomach in one strong fluid motion. With enough force, the cable tie will break.

    <b><big>DUCK TAPE</big></b>
    Duck tape is usually the initial method of restraint, as it is the simplest one to apply, and it is especially effective if wrapped in layers.

    If you have duck tape on your mouth, try opening your mouth as wide as possible. If you open your mouth large enough, the edges of the tape will come off your lips. You can then close your mouth to put the tape inside your mouth and "eat" the tape off your face. If the tape is very tightly stuck to your face, curl your lips in and lick the tape until the stickiness wears off.

    If your wrists are tied together, raise your arms until they are straight in front of you. Yank them inwards, pulling your shoulders and elbows behind you. Try to get this right the first time, otherwise you may just crumple up the tape and make it even more difficult to tear. Otherwise, do this repeatedly until you are able to tear the tape apart or have loosened it enough to slip out.

    If your ankles are tied tightly together and you cannot slip your feet out, squat all the way down in one strong motion. Try to get this right the first time, otherwise you may just crumple up the tape and make it even more difficult to tear. Otherwise, do this repeatedly until you are able to tear the tape apart or have loosened it enough to slip out.
    
    <b><big>ROPE</big></b>
    If your wrists are tied together, straighten your arms in front of you and start rubbing your palms violently. You may be able to shimmy out of your restraints. If your ankles
"
</string>
</resources>